Never forget why you are the church.
I'll turn your Bibles to Romans 12.
Romans 12.
I need y'all to buckle up because, uh, it's going to
be, it's going to be a fun one this morning.
Someone say, amen.
We jump back into our study and I want to remind us exactly where we are.
Uh, in the study of Romans, you know,
we me and Jack and Billy were joking about, well, they were
joking at 1st and they didn't think I heard them, I guess, but I did hear them.
They were talking junk about how long we've been in Robans.
I wonder, I wonder how many, you know, verses we're going to go over today.
And I'll tell you, we're going to go over 3 words today.
Amen?
And so Romans chapter 12.
The study as a whole, the book of Romans,
we're looking at the foundational theology of the gospel.
That's been since the 1st chapter, 1st verse.
If you want to sum up Paul's letter to Rome.
It is a very simple phrase, and that is the gospel of Jesus Christ.
We have taken our time unfolding the various and complex
layers of God's plan for salvation and what it
means for both the saved and the lost.
I need you to realize something.
The gospel is going to impact the lost and the saved.
In other words, those who reject the gospel, they're
going to spend eternity in hell.
Those who receive the gospel, they're going to spend eternity
with Jesus in heaven.
In other words, every single person who's ever been created,
is going to be impacted by the fact that Jesus lived.
He died, and he rose again.
Someone say amen to that.
So we got to understand it's not just for the saved, it's
not just for the lost, it's for every person he's created.
Now, we have spent several weeks already in Romans 12 with
the theme of the impact of the gospel.
But within this theme, we are in another layer of
the study, and we are looking at the impact of the gospel specifically
in our relationships with each other.
God made us relational.
God made us to have friendships,
to have relationships.
God made us to be a family.
You do realize that God created the 1st couple and he
created the 1st family.
They weren't perfect, but they were a family.
We're not perfect here at Cedar Grow, but we are a family.
Sin has messed up every area of relationship in our society.
It doesn't take long to watch the news, to look at social
media, just the people watch for a moment to realize,
man, sin has taken its toll.
So we must go back to what God desires regarding
how we interact with each other.
So far, we've looked at 4 commandments found in verses 10 through 11.
So we're going to look at it.
Romans chapter 12, starting in verse 10, somebody say, read.
Be kindly affectionate one to another with brotherly love.
In honor of preferring one another, not spotful
in business, fervent in spirit, serving the Lord.
If we're going to have the right relationship with each other, we must do
these several things.
First off, we must be devoted to each other, we must be
diligent, we must be fervent, and we must be serving the Lord.
Now, this morning, we're going to go over the title, and this
is the thought that we're going to kind of gather around, and it is rejoice,
again, I say, rejoice.
Let's pray.
Father, I thank you just for what's already happened this morning.
God, I pray that as I preach your word, Lord, you're glorified and honored.
God, I pray those that have ears to hear may they hear.
Just as my brother had just prayed over me.
Lord, God, I pray that there's someone here who's lost that today,
by confessing with their mouth that Jesus is Lord, believing
in their heart that God raised him from the dead.
God, I pray today they're saved.
God, we thank you, we trust you.
We don't doubt, we don't waver.
Since you say we pray.
Amen.
This morning, we move on to the next 3 commandments.
If you look at Romans chapter 12, verse 12, it says this, rejoicing
in hope, patient and tribulation, continuing
instant in prayer.
Now, before we break these down, I want to point something out this morning.
If you simply take a quick glance at this verse, it almost seems out of place.
These 3 commandments seem to be commandments to us personally.
In other words, what do these 3 commandments
have to do with our relationship to each other?
Well, can I 1st say something that I want you to understand?
If you're taking notes, you want to write this down.
Your personal walk with Christ impacts
those around you.
Let me say that one more time for you.
Your personal walk with Christ impacts those
around you.
You don't get to be a lone ranger.
God designed a church to be an interlocking family of faith
where each person affects the other.
Last week before service, my friend, brother Shane,
text me a scripture and explanation that was very eye-opening.
He calls me all the time.
We talk almost every day and it's always, he's like, hey, you ready for a nugget and I say, yeah.
And so he gives me a scripture and we talk about it and we debate it and we
really lift each other up in that.
But he took me to John 17.
And John 17, verse 17 through 19 says
this, Jesus is praying for his disciples, right?
We call this the priestly prayer.
He says it sanctify them through thy truth.
Thy word is truth.
As thou hast sent me into the world, even so have I
also sent them into the world.
Remember, this is Jesus speaking.
If you have a Bible, red letters, they will be read here.
And for their sakes, I sanctify myself
that they also might be sanctified through the truth.
Now just hold on for a moment while we expose the beautiful truth here.
What is sanctification?
Well, that word sanctify in John 17 literally means
to consecrate, to make holy, to sanctify
hallow, treat as holy.
It describes the divine act of setting aside as sacred.
When we talk about sanctification, we talk about it as a
process, the more we learn about God, the more
we know the truth, therefore the more holy we are to become.
What does it mean to be holy?
That is something that is holy is to be something or someone that
is set apart, like we just said, to sacred use,
to be used by God.
You do realize God desires you to be holy.
That means God desires to use you for his will and glory.
Not me, not just the front row Baptist,
not just the mineral row, the back row Baptist, every
single person in here.
God desires you to be holy so he can use you for his glory.
Now, again, what does this have to do with our point?
Well, remember the point.
Your personal walk of Christ impacts those around you.
Your holiness matters to those around you.
If you don't believe it, look again at what Jesus prays.
And this is Jesus Christ himself.
Okay, son of man, son of God.
Okay, the Messiah.
He says this, and for their sakes.
I sanctify myself.
that they also might be sanctified through the truth.
See, we so often looked at sanctification.
Inwardly.
In other words, I want to become more like Christ.
Have we ever thought about the fact that according to the words of Jesus,
the more you become like Christ, the more you can help someone else
become like Christ.
See, Paul kind of said it like this.
He said, hey, follow me as I follow Jesus.
You understand what I'm saying?
That what we're seeing here in John 17, but for whose sakes,
the disciple sakes.
Listen, your walk with Christ, your sanctification has a direct effect
on those who are closest to you and those who are watching from afar.
Well, I don't care what people think about me.
You know, there are certain sayings and phrases
that Christians say that when you say it, someone
may not tell you in that moment, but they think it.
You sound ridiculous.
You understand what I'm saying?
This is one of those phrases.
When I hear someone say, well, I don't care what anyone thinks about me.
You're sadly, you don't understand
the Christian walk, then.
Let me explain for a second.
If you have that notion, if you have that mindset in your
life, you better be living up to the God's holy standard of holiness in your life.
Because to not care means that you're showing him what it's about.
Well, I don't have to care because I'm holy like he is holy.
Well, if you're like me and I'm like you, what that means is
we got to watch our steps, amen?
See, we're not living perfectly.
So understand a concept of it doesn't matter what people think
is absolute nonsense.
I'm not saying that you build your life upon the opinions of others.
What I'm saying is people better see Jesus than you.
It does not matter, it does matter.
Sorry, what your brothers and sisters in Christ think about you.
Why?
Because what they think about you is really what they know about you.
It matters what the law thinks about you.
What if all they knew about Jesus is what they knew about you.
It matters, does it not?
The modern cultural Christianity teaching is that Jesus is only for me.
I can have my own understanding of and with God,
and I want you to know this is a lie straight from the pits of hell.
You don't get to have your own agreement.
You don't get to have your own understanding of God.
There is one way, one truth, and one life.
That's Jesus.
is the truth.
Amen.
So therefore, listen, we can debate certain things,
but we better be to this book because that's what he desires us
to be.
Your walk with Christ encourages others to walk with Christ.
How are you walking?
Let me ask you this.
How are those closest to you walking?
Listen, this convicts me.
How is my wife walking with Christ?
So many times people say, well, you know what?
That's her walk with Christ, and I can't help what she does.
Listen, as a man of God, you better get to helping what she does spiritually
because she's following your lead.
Don't sit there and point the finger at her if you're not walking with Christ.
And if you are walking with Christ, bring her in on it.
Y'all are one flesh.
Well, you know, my kids are just going to be my kids.
Listen, hey, kids will be kids.
We can't control everything our kids do, but they better see us walking with Christ.
Listen, I got so, I got so, I was disciplining my daughter.
I don't know if you've ever done that with your kids.
Maybe some of you haven't.
That's the problem.
But anyway, so I was disciplining my daughter.
She's just kind of getting sassy.
She's kind of, she's struggling with the transition from 2 kids to 3 kids.
It's just happening, okay?
And so I was talking to her and I had all these verses in
my Bible marked out that I was going to giver.
And I said, listen, I want to read script.
I told her, I said, I never want to use this book as a weapon as a parent.
I want you to understand that we operate in this home, in this
house, in this family according to God's word because we believe it's truth.
you believe it's true?
She says, yes, amen.
I said, okay, I'm going to give you some scripture about your attitude
and all things, and we're going to talk about it.
She said, man, and she wrote her eyes, which I'm like, this is why you're in this room right now.
But either way, I said, why did you throw your eyes?
She said, I just I'd rather not read right now.
Now, I had to take a step back.
Because I just had to take a step back.
But either way, what happened is I instantly
got angry, obviously, but then instantly my heart broke because
obviously there is a miscommunication going on here.
And so God just put it on my heart, just love on it.
Now, again, we had to take some things away, right?
We didn't just, oh, well, we just let her do whatever.
No, no, no.
Like there's some there's some parameters that we've set until she adjusts her attitude.
But I also said, listen, I know you don't want to hear it, but I need you to know something.
It's what I told her.
I said I'm preaching the same word.
to 100 something people tomorrow, and not all of them want to hear it,
but every single one of us need it.
And so therefore, I know that you're irritated with me.
I know you're mad at me for because you just, you just, you
know, I took things away, but I need to know what God says because he loves you.
Now, listen, I'm not saying I'm perfect, and I'm not saying that happens all the time.
As a matter of fact, I shot myself last night.
Hey man, you see what I'm saying?
Because usually I just go berserk and we go crazy.
But no, listen, our walk with Christ affects those around us.
If your wife, if your
family is not walking with Christ, the 1st thing to do is not point the finger,
it's to look inward.
How am I walking in faith?
And so again, this makes these commandments all the more important for us.
So let's look at the verse again.
Romans 12, verse 12.
It says rejoicing and hope.
Patient and tribulation, continuing instant prayer.
So the 1st commandment we're going to talk about is this.
We must be rejoicing.
It says rejoicing and hope.
What does it mean to rejoice in hope?
Well, Paul mentions this back in Romans 5, verse 2.
It says, by whom also we have access by faith into this grace,
wherein we stand and rejoice in hope of the glory of God.
To fully comprehend this command, we have to look at what both these words mean.
What does it mean actually to rejoice.
Well, if you look at the Greek, it says, to rejoice, to
be glad, to be in a state of gladness, happiness or well-being.
By the way, I know we talk about all the time.
Well, God doesn't cause us to be happy and it's all about joy.
Can I tell you something?
It's not a bad thing to be happy as a believer.
You don't have to sit around with that sour joy all the time.
You can be happy in the Lord.
Someone say amen.
Did you know that God commands us to rejoice in scripture.
Isaiah 65, verse 18, but be glad and rejoice
forever in what I create.
That's not a suggestion.
That's not a recommendation.
That's not just wise counsel.
He says, but be glad and rejoice forever in what I create.
For behold, I create Jerusalem for rejoicing and her people for gladness.
Philippians 4, verse 4.
Rejoice in the Lord always.
Again, I will say rejoice.
First Thessalonians 516.
Rejoice, always.
Church, this is not a suggestion.
This is a commandment.
The command to rejoice is not contingent on circumstance or outcome.
Now hear me.
Well, preacher, if you knew what I was going through, you wouldn't blame me for not rejoicing.
I want to slow down just for a moment.
You may be going through something that you feel no one understands or even cares about.
It may be it may be like that you feel as though you are
the exception to this rule.
Well, God has put this on me, so how could he expect
me to rejoice and be glad.
I need you to hear me this morning.
God's word and admonition is for you just like it is for everyone else.
There's nothing you can go through that is too great for God.
There is nothing you can go through that voids you from the blessing of
faithful obedience to his word.
What I am trying to say is this.
Rejoice even in the dark times.
Rejoice even when you hurt.
Rejoice even when you feel weak.
Rejoice even when you are going through the fire.
The Bible tells us, rejoice always.
Now.
Remember the definition of rejoice.
Rejoice, be glad, be in a state of gladness, happiness or well-being.
Now, I want you to notice, okay?
I was homeschooled for most of my educational career.
So I, you know, you think I'd be good at English, but I'm really not.
That's why no one is able to see my notes because when I used to handwrite them, you
wouldn't be able to read them because I don't know how to spell things.
So, but right here, what kind of word is this?
If you look at that, it says VB.
You see the VB?
What does that mean?
That means verb.
Now I'm not trying.
trying to insult your intelligence.
What I'm trying to say is this.
Sometimes we look at scripture and we don't realize that it is so practical
that we can actually live it out.
What is a verb?
A verb is the word in a sentence that functions by way of expressing action.
Yes, I have to look that up.
Why does this matter?
If we look at the definition closer?
At this Greek word, it brings a deeper understanding.
So if you look at it, there's always like an explanation of the depth of it.
So this kind of rejoicing in this term, what
it means is it's not only a feeling and expression of
joy, but hear me, also an action, one
chooses.
Did you know it is okay to feel?
Somehow we have taken the gift of feeling that God has given us
and either made it taboo or the foundation to our walk with Christ?
In other words, there's 2 ends of inspection with feelings.
Either you feel, and that's all you care about is if I don't feel it, then I'm not it.
And if I do feel that I am it.
Listen, that's a dangerous way to walk with the Lord, because you're not always going to feel it.
And then you have the other the other end where feelings have
no no place in the church and everything should be decent
and orderly in such a way that it's all just not, you know, fun
and this and that, there's no place for that in God's church either.
But it's okay to feel.
There are those who say feelings have nothing to do with
your walk and there are those who only pursue them to validate
their relationship with God.
Both are dangerous and not God's desire.
It is okay to feel.
It is okay to be worshiping Jesus and get those Holy Ghost goosebumps
as you acknowledge and proclaim who Jesus is and what he's done for you.
Has anyone ever gotten Holy Ghost goosebumps?
You know what I'm talking about?
If you haven't, what's wrong with you?
Let me just tell you something.
I love it.
It's okay to read a scripture and feel so excited about
it that you have to call a friend and share what God has just spoke to you about.
It is okay to shout because you can't keep the feeling of gratitude
in any longer.
It is okay to fill in all of God when you see him work in your life with someone else's.
Guys, it's okay to feel.
especially when God's working in your life.
However, feelings that are not founded on a foundation of truth and
devotion to the Lord can become egocentric and selfish very quickly.
Let me give you an example.
Anyone ever heard of a student versus faculty game?
So I use that, I didn't get invited this year.
That's okay.
I guess that's seeing the weight gain and all the things is slowing down.
You know what I'm saying?
But, uh, I usually play with the
Carol Oakland student versus faculty.
And, you know, of course, they're middle schoolers, right?
So we don't lose.
We got close one time.
It's because this kid who was a decent shooter became,
you know, Steph Curry and just didn't miss and it kind of made
us a little nervous there for a second.
But that's okay.
We just beat him up in halftime and went back to the 2nd half and won.
Anyway, but just kidding.
That's the thing.
But Jack, you remember these games.
Didn't we beat y'all?
Pretty good too, huh?
Amen.
All right.
Anyway, so.
There was one, I'll never forget.
So I am a hype person.
I like to scream and holler and and, you know,
kind of jump and stuff and and look at you and just go crazy
and stuff and I do a cool thing on the court, whatever, right?
And so I like doing that.
Well, I noticed that I was playing in this game.
And I would score or I'd make a cool little, you know,
pass or I'd do whatever it is, hit a three, whatever it is.
And man, I would just go crazy and hype, man, I feel like I was on top of the world.
Yes, these are 6th to 8th graders, whatever.
But either way, like I felt like I was just a guy, man.
And I'm running up and down the court like it ain't no one's business.
I'm talking about just screaming, stomping, doing all things.
Then all of a sudden, my heart said, you better stop.
And I started like kind of getting a little bit dizzy.
And then someone came up to me and said, Jake, are you good?
I'm like, yeah, I'm good.
I was like, let's let me sit down for a second.
Man, listen, I couldn't handle it.
I mean, I straight up, almost lost my life on that court.
Why?
Think about it.
Because I had no foundation of basketball cardio before that day.
So I'm sitting there.
The one time of year that I play, and I'm
playing like I've played every single day of my life.
And it caught up with me quick.
Now you say, what kind of dumb illustration is that?
Well, 1st off, here's the thing.
You can come in church all you want, put on a big old show.
Listen, if there's not a foundation of the daily walk with Christ,
all it is is a show.
You understand what I'm saying?
But the beautiful part about it is this.
As you continue walking with Christ day by day, as
you continue to get closer to him and become more holy, as time
goes by, then you come into this corporate gathering.
And all it is, is an overflow bubbling of the
Holy Spirit within you, giving your life to Christ over, not
not being saved, but just sacrificially living for Christ.
Listen, there's something special about that.
So if we are to rejoice always, how do we do that and we don't feel like it, though?
We don't miss this church.
It's a very easy explanation.
We choose to.
Amen?
When you don't feel like rejoicing,
The Bible says rejoice anyway and choose to do so.
No matter if it's a good day or terrible day, whether we slept good or
we didn't sleep at all, our life is going well
or it's an absolute train wreck, we choose to rejoice.
There are a few decisions that have massive impact on a person's life.
One of these decisions if you have done this before, if you haven't, then
it is what it is, but is who to marry and build a life with.
Pretty big decision.
Amen.
Oof.
We need to do marriage counseling.
Pretty big decision, amen?
Okay, pretty big decision.
There is an age old lie that this world has peddled regarding marriage.
We have propped up this idea of falling
out of love with each other.
Why are you leaving him?
I just don't love him anymore.
Why are you leaving her?
Well, I just I've just fallen out of love with her.
That's the that's what the world says is okay.
Let me, let me explain something.
I want to tell you a difficult truth.
Falling out of love does not matter more
than the decision you made of commitment to that person.
Let me say that again for you.
Falling out of love does not matter more than the decision you made of
commitment to that person.
What do we do wedding ceremony?
What is the most precious moments in the entire wedding?
And if you ask me, it's the vows.
So you look at the vows.
What are some of those popular vows out there?
It says this.
I name, take you name.
Thats husband, wife, right?
To have in a hole from this day forward for better, for
worse, for richer, for poorer, in
sickness, and in health, to love and to cherish till death do us part.
I need you to understand something.
That encompasses every high and low of life right there.
And in a vow, you make a decision to promise that.
As a matter of fact, I have the ceremony notes right here.
Ceremony notes that were used for me and Heather and also for
many of you who are married today.
I done many of your marriages and done the officiating
on a lot of them.
And so you remember this, but when we look at this, it says this right here.
It says, do you both so promise that together you will set the
Bible standard for your marriage, pursue to build a Christian home, submitting
one to another in the fear of God, allowing Christ to be the head?
His word to be the ruinous church to be central in your life.
Do you so promise?
Listen, if you didn't want to, there's a space between that
and the next part of you saying, no, I don't promise.
I can't do this.
But you know what we do?
We say, yes, I so promise.
We choose to make this commitment.
We look at this right here and this is where they repeat after me.
I love you.
I believe that you are God's gift to me.
I take you to be my wedded wife or husband.
I promise to love you like Christ left the church and gave himself for it.
I promised to put you 2nd only to Jesus Christ.
I promised to love Jesus so I can rightfully love you until God calls us home.
I am yours, and you are mine to this.
I promise to be true.
In other words, the decision that we make.
Now it can be based on feelings.
But if you've been married or have been in a relationship for any amount of time.
you know, feelings fade.
Now, why does any of this matter?
Because when you vow these vows, You chose to do so.
Allow me to make a note of clarification here.
You may be here and you have experienced an abusive or adulterous marriage that had to end.
There's no browbeating for you.
There is grace for you.
I understand that you are not a 2nd class saint.
There is no hierarchy in the family of God, but your feelings do
not override your vows.
Ecclesiastes 5, verse 4 and 5, when you make a vow
to God, do not be late in paying it for he takes no delight
in fools, pay what you vow.
It is better that you should not vow than you should vow and not pay.
Numbers 30, verse 2, if a man makes a vow to the Lord or takes an oath
to bind himself with a binding obligation.
He shall not violate his word.
He shall do it according to all that precedes out of his mouth.
Psalm 76, verse 11.
Make vows to the Lord your God and fulfill them.
James 5, verse 12, but above all, my brethren,
do not swear either by heaven or by earth or by any other oath, but
let your yes be yes and your no be no so that you may not
fall under judgment.
You understand what we're talking about here?
It's better not to make a vow than to make a vow and break it.
I believe a lot of marriages and a lot of a lot of friendships
and a lot of a lot of people would be healed if they would stop
looking at the other person and make sure they're keeping their vow.
You say, well, I didn't make no vow to God.
Hey, when you get married in the United States and I put religious
ceremony right there, what you're doing is you are saying in sight
of man and those that are around there and God that you're committing to this person.
Y'all with me this morning.
Again, I understand marriage can get difficult.
Marriage can get hard.
I'm not saying, listen, there's a whole nother message here.
God may permit, but he never promotes it when
we talk about divorce, but all I'm telling you is we make a vow, he better keep it.
But in the culture that we live in today, there is a lack of accountability, the decisions we
make, or even worse, we live our lives refusing to commit to anything.
We say, well, maybe.
If something better doesn't come up.
Listen, you tell me that, you know what I mean?
instantly thinking, you ain't going to be there.
You understand what I'm saying?
If you came to me and said, hey, preacher, I've got a,
I've got a loved one who's on their deathbed, and I need you to come
pray with them because you're their pastor and I love you.
And I said, man, hey, I hope to be there.
I sure does sound like a good plan, man.
I, uh, you know, right now I'm kind of busy, but I'll be there when I can.
How would you take that?
You wouldn't take it good.
Are you with me this morning?
Like, this is very common.
You'd be like, what are you talking about?
No, no, listen, we better we better committed in our life.
This goes for every area.
There's a reason why Sunday morning is so difficult for many because
they have yet to commit themselves fully to the Lord in that way.
So when Sunday morning comes around and you don't feel like it, because
you haven't decided in your heart and made a commitment to the Lord's
day, it's easy just to stay home.
But when you decide that the gathering of saints together is
not based on feelings, but obeying God's command to not neglect the gathering.
Things change very quickly.
It's great when you feel good.
But when your feelings betray you, you have to lean on faith in God's word.
The Bible commands us, no matter how we feel, we are to
rejoice.
But there's more to this command.
Romans 12 verse 12, rejoicing in hope.
It is one thing to say, rejoice because God says so, but you aren't,
but aren't you glad his word explains and gives reason for our rejoicing?
There's have you ever told your kid, hey, do this.
And why?
Because I said so.
You ever said that?
Some of y'all said every day of your life, right?
My dad used to love saying that.
Hey, dad, why we got to do this?
Because I said so, son.
Well, okay.
I still don't know though.
What I'm trying to say is this, God doesn't do that to us.
God explains it.
Look, look again, what it says.
Rejoicing in hope.
It is one thing to say rejoice because God says so.
But we ought to rejoice in hope.
We know what the word rejoice means, but what about the word hope?
Look at the, um, the meaning of hope.
It's hope.
But this noun expresses the idea of hope and expectation.
I want to focus on the part of expectation here.
Did you know God wants us to expect him to work in our lives?
Have you ever heard the saying, you're either coming out of a
storm in a storm right now or about to enter into a storm?
I've said that from the pulpit.
Have you ever heard that?
Listen, that's a pretty discouraging way to live life, is it not?
Well, if you're not hurting right now.
You're about to hurt.
You know what I mean?
Like, we tell each other that like, man, God bless you.
Why are you telling me these things?
Right?
But understand, listen, let's think about the weather since we talked about that.
There was a time not too long ago that it was hot and there was no rain for weeks.
Do you remember that?
Some of y'all was praising the Lord because you didn't have to mow your yard for like 3 weeks in a row.
The grass was dead, everything was gone, right?
At no time during that drought did I think this was going
to be how it was for the rest of our life in Lebanon, Tennessee.
It may have gone longer than we expected, but we expected
God to send the rain.
Guess what happened?
It rained.
Understand something.
When the thunder begins to roar and the lightning makes the sky shine
on throughout the night and you wake up to the calm serenity of
the early morning, we are not surprised, why?
Because we expected the storm to pass.
Earlier this year, snow and ice covered the ground.
The entire town looked completely different.
when it all melted and went away, we were not shocked.
Why?
We expected it to go.
Summer gives way to fall.
Fall gives way to winter.
Winter gives way to spring, just to all go back to fall.
We expect the change in seasons.
Why?
Because that's how God has worked out his creation.
So what does this mean for us?
David understood trial and tribulation.
Some were self-inflicted, but many were out of his control.
In Psalm 30, we're moving very quickly here.
Psalm 30 is a beautiful psalm in your Bible.
It probably has this heading.
Thanksgiving for deliverance from death, a psalm,
a song of the dedication of the house, a psalm of David.
In other words, this is a psalm dedicating the temple
in Jerusalem.
Now, historians are torn on whether this is written by David
or about David, but with all we know about David, I
lean towards him being the author of this psalm.
So listen to what he wrote in Psalm 30.
It says this in verse one, I will extol you, 0 Lord, for
you have lifted me up and have not let my enemies rejoice over me.
Oh, Lord my God, I cried to you for help and you healed me.
Oh, Lord, you have brought up my soul from Sheol.
You have kept me alive, that I would not go down to the pit, sing
praise to the Lord.
You is godly ones, and give thanks to his holy name.
Verse 5 for his anger is, but for a moment, his favor is for a lifetime.
Weeping may last for the night, but a shadow of joy comes
in the morning.
I need everyone to lean in for the next few moments of this message.
It's obvious that in this psalm,
David had been delivered from some sort of sickness, they say,
or something happened to where he was about to taste death and
God lifted him up, out of it.
But that's not the point that I want to make here, for you who know your Bible real good.
You know that David did not build the temple.
It's son Solomon did.
See, David was a fighter.
You didn't want to see David on the battlefield because that probably means if you're
wearing the wrong, you know, uniform, you probably dead.
You know what I'm saying?
Like, you're going to get a stone in your temple.
But David was that guy.
Solomon was a builder.
David wanted so bad to build a house for God.
Yet God told them you're not going to, but Solomon will.
Y'all with me?
But David still rejoiced.
Why?
Because he had hope.
Even though the temple was not built in his lifetime, he
expected it to get done.
Are y'all with me this morning?
Understand that David's life was full of intense moments, both good and bad.
He was a man after God's own heart.
He was the most conquering king.
Israel has ever had, literally, when Jesus came,
they were saying, hey, we want you to be more like David.
That's why they rejected him because he wasn't delivering them from Rome.
Like, they thought that he was going to.
That's how that's how high they saw David in their in their rankings,
but understand this.
He had an abundance of talent and skills, yet he also had much strength,
family conflict, grave sins and pressure from every angle.
But what did he write?
For his anger is but for a moment.
His favors for a lifetime.
Weeping may last for the night, but a shadow of joy
comes in the morning.
Church, we are commanded to
rejoice in hope.
The dark will give way to the light.
The pain will not last forever.
The hurt will be healed.
The conflict will cease.
The pressure will subside.
We are to believe it and expect it.
And here's the thing.
If not in this life, just like David.
We can expect, and we see Jesus.
Everything will be new.
Therefore, we can rejoice.
So this morning, I wonder, Are you choosing
to rejoice?
Do you walk around and every time something doesn't go your way, you become
sour and bitter and resentful and you forget
all the things that God promises, you forget all the things God said and
you just, you sit there in your feelings and and you
think, okay, this is just what I am right now.
No, no, no.
Understand joy comes in the morning.
His anger is real.
His chastisement is real.
Our sins effect on our life is real.
But joy comes in the morning.
What David is trying to tell us is, rejoice in hope.
Just like Paul wrote.
So what are you rejoicing in?
Are you rejoicing?
What has Ben Eis closed all over this place?